Okay, so here we are in a new chat and
we're going to start by saying please
read agents.md
then read
the plan
and let me know
any questions
before we start part eight. Okay, let's
let it see what it wants to come back
with. It's thinking about that.
Okay.
Uh right. So first of all for the 2
plus2 integration test you want it fully
mocked or should the backend endpoint or
mocking actually
I want it to go all the way
to open router.
No mocking. Let's check
we can get an answer
from the model. That's important. I saw
that before when we were looking at the
plan. I remember thinking I don't like
the fact that it's mocking it there. So,
I'm super happy that it asked, should it
be under API AI or API chat? Uh API chat
sounds great. Do you want the open
router base URL configurable or
hardcoded? Uh uh hardcoded
is good for now.
Please
note these answers
in plan
MD and proceed with part 8. Exciting.
And there's something comforting about
knowing that we've got a completely
fresh chat. So the context window is
empty or it's not completely empty
because it's got the agents MD and the
plan that it's loading in there. And
that means we're making really efficient
use of the space. It's not cluttered
with all of that stuff about worrying
about drag and drop, which would have
really filled up lots and lots of room.
And sure, it would have been compressed
and it would have been summarized, but
it would still been hogging space. Now,
it feels like it's nice and efficient.
We've got good good use of space. We
we're positioning our agent for success,
codeex for success. And I will see you
in a minute when it's done with part
eight. Okay. And I just experienced the
good and the bad of restarting the
conversation. You may have had this
experience, too, if you're following
along with me. Exactly. it it seemed
faster and more accurate somehow. It
feels almost like it sort of decluttered
its brain to reset the conversation, but
then it also got stuck trying to run
tests because it forgot the right way to
start the server and it took a while.
Took 5 minutes of thrashing around to
figure that out. So, I've asked it to
update its own plan MD to make sure
that's clear for the future and I've
asked it to confirm the tests have all
run. Open router is working. Part 8 is
done. So we'll keep our edits. We'll do
a git status
and we will do a git add dot a git
commit minus m part 8 complete.
And now it's time to go on to to part
nine. Please proceed with part nine. And
off it goes. Let's uh come back in a
second when that's done. Okay. And more
progress. Apparently part nine is done
too. and it had done some mocked tests
and I had to prompt it to ask it to
actually test against open router that
it claims it has now done and we won't
know for sure until we've added part 10
which is the user interface for us to do
that and that's what's coming up next.
It's a big moment for us. So I'm just
going to again do do git. We're doing
we're being very careful about
checkpointing at each point. So get
status. I'm just going to press the keep
button here. I'm going to do get add dot
I'm going to do get
commit minus m plan uh part n
is complete
and then and then it's time for us to go
ahead with with the part 10. Okay,
please proceed
with part 10. Very exciting. I will see
you in a second. Okay. All right. So, we
should be done. Let's have a look. Do
you think it's going to work? Do you
think it's going to work? Let's find
out. Let us go and uh run scripts
slashstart-mac
for me. And something is starting.
There's no errors that I can see so far.
Let's go over here. Let me go to
localhost 8000. Here we have our usual
login screen. We'll come in like this.
We're going to get the usual password
error.
Okay, we see a camban board, but
something is different. There's an AI
assistant chat on the right. Let's just
say hi there. Enter. See what happens.
Hello. How can I help you with your
board today? There's an AI at the other
end of this. We have an AI assistant
app. People pay big money for this
stuff. All right, let's see. What are we
going to ask it? Uh, please please uh
summarize
my project
for me. Okay, so we're asking it to do
that. Well, it's pretty fast, isn't it?
Your project spans five columns.
Backlog, in progress, review, and done.
It It seems to uh seems to have that
about right, doesn't it? Okay. I I I
like it so far. All right. Now I'm going
to say please move the this thing here
the gather customer gather customer
signals
card from backlog to let's go all the
way over to done. We're going to move
this guy here all the way over to done.
Let's see what happens. Bam. Do you see
that? It moved. It moved.
The magic of AI. There we have it. We
have a camb board. This data is
persisted to disk. It's got it's got a
database behind it. It's running in a
Docker container with a front end and a
back end. And it's got an AI assistant
we can chat with to rearrange and
organize our project. It is an app. And
if you don't believe me, that of course
you shouldn't. We we should bring up a
new tab all together. Go to localhost.
Come in not as ed as user and password.
Sign in. Here we go. And we're happy to
see that gather customer signals is
still over here in the done column
proving that it has been persisted to
disk. Beautiful. Now the thing is this
is not the end. This is the beginning.
You will have something different to
this. Of course it will look different.
It will well it probably won't look
different because you you started with
the same camman studio as me. But now
this is a canvas on which you can build
and you can keep working. It looks like
we should try and do some work to resize
these columns. We might want the chat to
show when it's thinking maybe stream
back results. We might want to we can
add in different users so you can log in
as different users that it's all ready
for that. You could have different
canban boards adding on boards. You can
see how just doing the same thing
cranking the handle in the way we've
been doing. We've done a full pass with
the minimal starting point and now you
can add and add and add and I hope you
see I hope you get this sense that this
is the beginning of something that could
be a complete full app. It has users. It
has functionality. It has a database.
This is something that could easily be
turning into a product that people would
pay for. It's a real useful uh
commercial app. We have here some
project management software with a cam
on board with an AI assistant chat to
work on your project with you. And this
has been all to to set you in motion for
vibe coding for building these kinds of
apps. What we're going to be learning
about in in the upcoming weeks is taking
this to the next level. If if we look at
the the the main results in here, the
main piece of Python code is one module
called main.py. And I have to be honest
with you, it's a bit of a mess. And
that's why it's good to take things step
at a time because if I were going to
keep going now, I would stop and tell it
this needs to be refactored. This
definitely is something of a disaster
here. It's an enormous great uh uh look
at look at here. You can see the
summary. It's really shoved everything
in this one Python module which has many
different concerns. It seems to me I
don't know why it's gone down this path,
but it seems like it's a major gaff that
needs to be fixed. What we would do
typically is we would have another agent
that's responsible for doing a code
review and it would definitely point
this out. But otherwise, if I were
taking this forwards, the first thing I
would do is get this restructured so
that it's organized in a better way. Um,
along with fixing up some of the user
interface, adding in users, and then
perhaps having a a remote database like
in in in Superbase. So, all of those
things can be done, and these are all
things that you should do. That is the
assignment for the end of week one. Take
this now. Take it further. Add on. Take
it in direction that you want. You don't
need to add in users if you don't need
to. You could ask it to add instructions
for for deploying this. Deploy it to
versel. Once you've got something in a
container, it's so easy to deploy
anywhere to AWS appr runner to GCP cloud
run to wherever you want. It can give
you instructions, step-by-step
instructions, and it can even do the
deployment itself if you want. So, all
of these things, you should take it in
some direction and then message me and
tell me what you've done. I can't wait
to hear how you've taken this and made
it into a proper product that could even
perhaps be monetized. And as you roll up
your sleeves to do this assignment, let
me leave you with an inspiring final
tweet from Andre. This is actually this
was at the bottom of what I showed you
before. I held this back. He ends by
saying, "Where does this leave us? LLM
agent capabilities like Claude and
Codeex especially and he's referring to
Codex the model the one that we use
today not not Codex the platform so so
we we we uh we were doing that today
they have crossed some kind of threshold
of coherence around December of last
year causing a phase shift in software
engineering the intelligence part
suddenly feels quite a bit ahead of all
the rest of it and so then he lists out
the other stuff that we're going to be
coming on to so this is going to be a
high energy year as the industry figures
out how to bring together this new
capability and and factor it into all
the sorts of uh integrations and
workflows and processes. So very
exciting times indeed and I hope you are
super inspired by seeing what codeex was
able to do in GitHub copilot and now
you're taking that yourself and taking
it forwards. And with that that is a
wrap on week one. That completes day
five. You have now vibe coded for fun in
that you built a first-p person shooter.
You built a personal website with a
digital twin. And then you've just built
the beginnings, an MVP of what could be
a real commercial product, project
management software with an AI
assistant, a canban board, drag and
drop. It's it's the whole works and
you're you're taking it even further
right now. So that is fantastic.
Congratulations on on on making it to
the end of week one. Week two is huge.
We make the transition from Vibe coding
to Vibe engineering. We're going to be
using Claude Code in Ang. And I love
Claude Code and I can't wait to show it
to you. We're going to be coding in a
CLI as it gets super professional. And
for people that already used it before,
I've got a treat in store for you as
we're going to really roll up sleeves
and get into it. And I can't wait. And
with that, that concludes week one. You
are 33% of the way through this course.
You are on the way to being an agentic
engineer. I will see you for week two.